Catalog of the Walt Whitman Literary Manuscripts in The Charles E. Feinberg Collection of the Papers of Walt Whitman, 1839-1919, Library of Congress, Washington, DC.
Published by The Walt Whitman Archive in collaboration with the University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries.
- Literary File, 1841-1919, undated (Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37)
  - Old War-Dreams, about 1881; loc.00238; xxx.00286; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Old War-Dreams (1865-66). Proof.)
    Proof of Old War-Dreams with note at bottom in Whitman's hand: "Walt Whitman's New Book." This poem was published first, in a different form, as In Clouds Descending, in Midnight Sleep in 1865-1866. In 1871 it appeared under the title In Midnight Sleep. The title Old War-Dreams was first applied in 1881.
  - Go forth, ye twain, about 1890; loc.00069; xxx.00383; poetry handwritten 3 leaves (Box 28, Folder On, On the Same, Ye Jocund Twain! (1891). A.MS. drafts.)
    An early draft of On, on the Same, Ye Jocund Twain!, which was published first in 1891. The draft is written on a letter from Albert Johannsen (dated March 22, 1890 ), and two opened envelopes (one postmarked April 27, 1890 ).
  - Go forth, ye twain, about 1890; loc.00072; xxx.00383; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder On, On the Same, Ye Jocund Twain! (1891). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft of On, on the Same, Ye Jocund Twain!, which was published first in 1891. On the verso is a note in Whitman's hand reading "to my 2d & last Annex for L of G."
  - On, on awhile ye jocund twain, about 1890; loc.00074; xxx.00383; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder On, On the Same, Ye Jocund Twain! (1891). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft of On, on the Same, Ye Jocund Twain!, which was published first in 1891.
  - On, on the same, ye jocund twain!, May 10, 1890; loc.00239; xxx.00383; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 28 x 22 cm (Box 28, Folder On, On the Same, Ye Jocund Twain! (1891). A.MS. drafts.)
    A late draft of On, on the Same, Ye Jocund Twain!, which was published first in 1891. This draft is signed and dated May 10, 1890.
  - On, On the Same, Ye Jocund Twain!, about 1891; loc.00240; xxx.00383; poetry handwritten 3 leaves 24 x 15 cm (Box 28, Folder On, On the Same, Ye Jocund Twain! (1891). Proof Sheets.)
    Three proof sheets of On, On the Same, Ye Jocund Twain!, first published in 1891. One proof has several corrections and a note for the printer; the other two proofs have no annotations.
  - [As I sail'd at night alone], undated; loc.00241; xxx.00739; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 19.5 x 10 cm (Box 28, Folder Ontario's Shores. A.MS. draft.)
    A few lines on the verso of a cancelled letter (the correspondent and date are unknown), beginning "As I sail'd at night alone." The relationship of this draft to Whitman's published work is unknown. The title on the Library of Congress's folder comes from the final line of the draft ("As I wander Ontario's shores alone at night") and does not suggest that this draft is related to By Blue Ontario's Shore.
  - Our Old Feuillage, between 1876-1881; loc.00242; xxx.00114; poetry handwritten 6 leaves 20.5 x 12.5 cm (Box 28, Folder Our Old Feuillage (1860). A.MS. corrected pages.)
    A bound copy of six leaves (the poem American Feuillage) from the 1876 edition of Leaves of Grass with multiple corrections and revisions, including the change of the title to Our Old Feuillage. The revisions reflect the poem as it appeared in the 1881 edition of Leaves of Grass. Our Old Feuillage has also been titled A Chant of National Feuillage and Chants Democratic No. 4.
  - Out from behind this Mask, between 1873-1876; loc.00244; xxx.00236; poetry handwritten 2 leaves (Box 28, Folder Out from Behind This Mask (1876). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft of the poem Out From Behind This Mask, first published in 1876.
  - Out from this Mask, between 1873-1876; loc.00245; xxx.00236; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Out from Behind This Mask (1876). A.MS. draft.)
  - Out From This Mask, between 1873-1876; loc.00246; xxx.00236; poetry handwritten 2 leaves (Box 28, Folder Out from Behind This Mask (1876). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft of the poem Out From Behind This Mask, first published in 1876, written on two leaves. On the verso is a draft of a letter Whitman sent to Webster Elmes on 14 August 1873, arranging for a substitute, following his stroke, to cover his work as a clerk in Washington, D. C.
  - [(Returning to my pages front once], between 1873-1876; loc.00088; xxx.00236; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Out from Behind This Mask (1876). A.MS. draft.)
  - Out from behind this Mask, between 1873-1876; loc.00247; xxx.00236; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Out from Behind This Mask (1876). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft of the poem Out From Behind This Mask, first published in 1876. The title is written in blue pencil.
  - [(Returning to my pages front once], between 1873-1876; loc.00248; xxx.00236; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Out from Behind This Mask (1876). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft of the poem Out From Behind This Mask, first published in 1876, written on two scraps pasted together.
  - [This designation of Myself], between 1873-1876; loc.00249; xxx.00236; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Out from Behind This Mask (1876). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft of lines from the poem Out From Behind This Mask, first published in 1876.
  - [here strange continents], between 1873-1876; loc.00250; xxx.00236; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Out from Behind This Mask (1876). A.MS. draft.)
  - Behind this Mask, between 1873-1876; loc.00251; xxx.00236; poetry handwritten 2 leaves (Box 28, Folder Out from Behind This Mask (1876). A.MS. draft.)
    Notes and trial lines for the poem Out From Behind This Mask, first published in 1876, written on the verso of a letter to Whitman from Minnie Vincent, dated Utica, New York, December 11, 1873, asking for an autograph).
  - Out From Behind This Mask, about 1876; loc.00252; xxx.00236; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 15.5 x 13.5 cm (Box 28, Folder Out From Behind this Mask (1876). Printed Copy.)
    A corrected copy of Out From Behind This Mask, cut from pages 24 and 25 of Two Rivulets and pasted together to make one page.
  - Over and through the burial chant, 1888; loc.00253; xxx.00393; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Over and Through the Burial Chant (1888). Printed Copy.)
    Clipped-out copy of Over and Through the Burial Chant from the August 12, 1888 issue of the New York Herald, with notations in Whitman's hand. The poem was later published as Interpolation Sounds.
  - The Patrol at Barnegat, about 1881; loc.00254; xxx.00140; poetry handwritten 3 leaves (Box 28, Folder Patroling Barnegat. (1880). A.MS. drafts.)
    An early draft entitled The Patrol at Barnegat, containing trial lines for the poem first published as Patrolling Barnegat in the April 1881 issue of Harper's Monthly Magazine. On the verso of one leaf is a letter to Whitman from E. H. Hames dated May 12, 1880.
  - The Patrol at Barnegat, about 1881; loc.00255; xxx.00140; poetry handwritten 3 leaves (Box 28, Folder Patroling Barnegat. (1880). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft entitled The Patrol at Barnegat, containing trial lines for the poem first published as Patrolling Barnegat in the April 1881 issue of Harper's Monthly Magazine. The draft was originally titled The Sea Beach Patrol, then The Sea Shore Patrol, and finally The Patrol at Barnegat. On the verso of the draft are two receipts from the Philadelphia Y.M.C.A., dated March 22, 1880 and April 15, 1880, and an unfinished letter from Whitman to John Burroughs, dated August 20.
  - The Patrol at Barnegat, about 1881; loc.00256; xxx.00140; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Patroling Barnegat. (1880). A.MS. drafts.)
    A heavily-corrected draft of the poem published as Patrolling Barnegat in the April 1881 issue of Harper's Monthly Magazine.
  - Patroling Barnegat, about 1881; loc.00258; xxx.00140; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 12 x 16 cm (Box 28, Folder Patroling Barnegat (1880). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof sheet of Patroling Barnegat, with a correction in Whitman's hand. The poem was first published as Patrolling Barnegat in the April 1881 issue of Harper's Monthly Magazine.
  - Patroling Barnegat, about 1881; loc.02403; xxx.00140; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 12 x 16 cm (Box 28, Folder Patroling Barnegat (1880). Proof Sheets.)
  - Paumanok, about 1888; loc.00259; xxx.00312; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 12 x 21 cm (Box 28, Folder Paumanok (1888). A.MS. copy.)
    Written in ink on a sheet of white paper, cut from a larger sheet, is a late draft of Paumanok, first published in 1888. It is signed in full at bottom. The word "personal" is partially encircled in the upper right-hand corner. In pencil on verso in another hand: " Feb 18, 1888 ."
  - Paumanok, about 1888; loc.00260; xxx.00312; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 22 x 14.5 cm (Box 28, Folder Paumanok (post-1888). Newspaper clipping.)
    A small newspaper clipping of Paumanok pasted onto a larger sheet of paper, with notes and corrections in Whitman's hand. Paumanok was first published in the New York Herald in 1888.
  - [Peace no more], undated; loc.00261; xxx.00740; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 16 x 19 cm (Box 28, Folder Peace No More, But Flag of War. A.MS. draft.)
    A draft beginning "Peace no more, but flag of war" written in pencil on a sheet of white paper, with a corner cut out, on which the last two lines of the poem had been written. On the verso is a list of words. The relationship of this draft to Whitman's published work is unknown.
  - [Mask with their lids thine eyes], about 1870; loc.00262; xxx.00594; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Penitenzia. A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of a poem never published in Whitman's lifetime, but published posthumously as [Mask with Their Lids]. The draft was evidently part of a larger notebook titled Penitenzia, but no other pages from such a notebook are present in this folder. The folder also contains two pages from Clifton Joseph Furness's book Walt Whitman's Workshop concerning the draft.
  - Pioneers! O Pioneers!, about 1865; loc.00263; xxx.00124; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 21 x 16.5 cm (Box 28, Folder Pioneers! O Pioneers! (1865). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of the first two stanzas of Pioneers! O Pioneers!, which was first published in 1865, written in ink on a rough, bluish piece of paper. On the verso is a note in pencil concerning wounded soldiers.
  - The Play-Ground, about 1846; loc.00264; xxx.00741; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20 x 16.5 cm (Box 28, Folder The Play-Ground (1846). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of The Play-Ground, nearly as it appeared in the Brooklyn Daily Eagle on June 1, 1846 (during Whitman's editorship of the paper). On the verso is a page of prose in Whitman's hand.
  - Prayer of Columbus, 1881; loc.00266; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 3 leaves (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. corrected pages.)
    Bound corrected proofs of Prayer of Columbus, which was published first in 1874. The title page, which follows Whitman's portrait, reads "Prayer of Columbus, by Walt Whitman, The Poet's Corrected Proof, 1881 ." The corrections are most likely for the 1881 edition of Leaves of Grass.
  - [By me], about 1874; loc.00267; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    A draft of lines from Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874.
  - [Thou knowest my], about 1874; loc.00268; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - [what is the guidance], about 1874; loc.00269; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - Columbus Prayer (ad 1503), about 1874; loc.00270; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    Notes on the title of the poem that became Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874.
  - Columbus Prayers (ad 1503), about 1874; loc.00271; xxx.00263; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    A draft of lines from Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874. On the verso is prose concerning "Nationality" and "Cohesion."
  - [A batter'd wreck'd old man], about 1874; loc.00272; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    A draft of lines from Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874. The lines are written on stationery from the Attorney General's office and on the verso are prose notes, one of which reads "Acknowledge our obligations to English & other foreign literature."
  - [My hand, my limbs grow nerveless], about 1874; loc.00273; xxx.00263; poetry poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    A heavily revised draft, written on two scraps pasted together, of lines for Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874. On the verso are prose notes beginning "Idea in each of the three papers." Whitman's intentions for these notes are unclear.
  - [Steersman unseen], about 1874; loc.00274; xxx.00263; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    A draft of lines from Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874. On the verso are prose notes beginning "Idea in each of the three papers."
  - [Be it with], about 1874; loc.00275; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - [What may be the end I know not], about 1874; loc.00276; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    A draft of lines from Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874. On the verso is a prose note reading "much of this stuff will come in the 'Notes.'"
  - [my end draws], about 1874; loc.00277; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - [my brain grows rack'd], about 1874; loc.00278; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - Pourtraiture of Columbus, about 1874; loc.00279; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    Prose notes concerning Whitman's idea for the poem Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874.
  - Pourtray Columbus, about 1874; loc.00280; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - [my altar here the bleak sea-sand], about 1874; loc.00281; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - [what do I know of life?], about 1874; loc.00282; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    A draft of lines from Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874. On the verso is a brief prose note mentioning "Lecturers—& their Style."
  - [Utter prostrate], about 1874; loc.00283; xxx.00263; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    A draft of lines from Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874. On the verso are Whitman's prose notes, now partially torn away, treating Personal[ism] and the Kalev[ala].
  - [The terminus now near], about 1874; loc.00284; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - [I am too full of woe], about 1874; loc.00285; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - [Thine now the helm], about 1874; loc.00286; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - [All my emprises], about 1874; loc.00287; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
  - [Haply the lifeless cross], about 1874; loc.00288; xxx.00263; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    A draft of lines from Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874. On the verso is prose about a "capacious class of mighty ministers of the mind."
  - [Poem—Columbus], about May, 1869; loc.00880; xxx.00263; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf 41 x 27 cm (Box 28, Folder Prayer of Columbus (1874). Marginalia.)
    Detached from Irish Republic 3, no. 5 (May 1869), 60: The Last Days of Columbus [abstract from Sir Arthur Phelps' book The Spanish Conquest in America, reprinted from Harper's Magazine]. Across left margin in Walt Whitman's hand: "Poems—Columbus—(? that name for piece)—make the poem an utterance of Columbus—there on Jamaica island (read first Ulysses, by Tennyson)." Some of the passages in the abstract are marked and underlined by Whitman. This is assumed to be the original idea of the poem Prayer of Columbus, first published in 1874.
  - [Priests!], about 1855; loc.00013; xxx.00119; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 10 x 20 cm (Box 28, Folder Priests! (1855). A.MS. draft.)
    These lines thematically resemble work of the 1855 edition of Leaves of Grass, specifically the final lines of the poem later called A Song for Occupations, but their specific relationship to Whitman's published work is unknown. These lines were posthumously published with the title [Until You Can Explain...] On the verso, Whitman jotted a note for a poem he planned to gather "for droppin[gs]."
  - [Here fretful], about 1888; loc.00014; xxx.00320; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 23 x 20 cm (Box 29, Folder Queries to My 70th Year (1888). A.MS. draft.)
    One page draft written in pencil on a sheet of coarse paper, with a notation in another hand at the very bottom ("297—Doubleday Queries to 70th Year"). The lines were revised and published as Queries to My Seventieth Year in 1888.
  - Resurgemus, about 1884; loc.00289; xxx.00144; poetry handwritten 2 leaves 24.5 x 14.5 cm (Box 29, Folder Resurgemus (1850). Clipping.)
    A clipping from the September, 1884 issue of the London magazine To-Day. Printed in the issue is Whitman's poem Resurgemus, and in Whitman's hand are some corrections and a bibliographic notation. The publication history of this poem is unusual: it was published first as Resurgemus in 1850, then untitled in the 1855 edition of Leaves of Grass, then as Poem of The Dead Young Men of Europe, the 72nd and 73rd Years of These States in the 1856 edition, and as Europe, The 72nd and 73rd Years of These States in the 1860 and subsequent editions. The appearance of the poem in an 1884 periodical under an old title is highly unusual.
  - A Riddle Song, 1880; loc.00015; xxx.00277; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 22 x 12 cm (Box 29, Folder A Riddle Song (1881). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft of the first five lines of A Riddle Song, first published in 1880. The draft is written in ink on a surface made by pasting three smaller pieces together. Another small fourth scrap is pasted to the opposite side.
  - A Riddle Song, about 1880; loc.00290; xxx.00277; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder A Riddle Song (1881). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof sheet of A Riddle Song, first published in 1880, with corrections in Whitman's hand.
  - The endless Catalogue Divine, about 1891; loc.00291; xxx.00404; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 25 x 19.5 cm (Box 29, Folder The Rounded Catalogue Divine Complete (1891). A. MS. drafts.)
    A badly stained draft of a poem published as The Rounded Catalogue Divine Complete in 1891.
  - The real earthly catalogue divine, 'complete', about 1891; loc.00017; xxx.00404; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder The Rounded Catalogue Divine Complete (1891). A. MS. drafts.)
    A draft of a poem published as The Rounded Catalogue Divine Complete in 1891, written in ink on a piece of paper to that of The endless Catalogue Divine (loc.00291), with a discarded envelope (addressed to Miss Olive Percival, 214 W. 2nd St., Los Angeles, CA) opened out and pasted to the bottom of the piece, and some corrections in both pencil and ink.
  - [casts off her moorings], about 1890; loc.00018; xxx.00380; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Sail Out for Good, Eidólon Yacht! (1888). A.MS. drafts and notes.)
    Trial lines for Sail Out for Good, Eidólon Yacht!, which was published first in 1891. On the verso is a letter from Harry C. Kochersperger dated June 27, 1890.
  - Sail forth O mystic yacht of me, about 1890; loc.00040; xxx.00380; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Sail Out for Good, Eidólon Yacht! (1888). A.MS. drafts and notes.)
    Trial lines for Sail Out for Good, Eidólon Yacht!, which was published first in 1891. On part of the page is prose that appears to be a journal entry. The rest, though, is dedicated to a draft of the poem, with the title written half way down the page: Sail forth O mystic yacht of me. On the verso is written "Walt Whitman, July 30 1890 " twice.
  - Sail out for Good Eidolon yacht, about 1891; loc.00041; xxx.00380; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Sail Out for Good, Eidolón Yacht! (1888). A.MS. drafts and notes.)
    Note regarding Sail Out for Good, Eidólon Yacht!, which was published first in 1891. Written on this small white sheet are the title of the poem (Sail out for good Eidólon yacht) and trial phrases for what appears to be a subtitle.
  - Salut Au Monde, about 1881; loc.00292; xxx.00110; poetry handwritten printed 13 leaves (Box 29, Folder Salut Au Monde (1886). A.MS. corrected pages.)
    Pages of Salut Au Monde! as printed in the 1871–72 edition of Leaves of Grass, heavily corrected for publication in the 1881–82 edition This poem had originally been published in 1856 under the title Poem of Salutation.
  - Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher, about 1887; loc.00294; xxx.00390; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf 15 x 14.5 cm (Box 29, Folder Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher (1891). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof of Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher, which was published first in 1887.
  - Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher, about 1887; loc.02413; xxx.00390; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf 15 x 14.5 cm (Box 29, Folder Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher (1891). Proof Sheets.)
  - Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher, about 1887; loc.02414; xxx.00390; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf 15 x 14.5 cm (Box 29, Folder Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher (1891). Proof Sheets.)
  - Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher, about 1887; loc.04122; xxx.00390; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf 15 x 14.5 cm (Box 29, Folder Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher (1891). Proof Sheets.)
  - The Singing Thrush, February 28, 1873; loc.00019; xxx.00256; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 12 x 19 cm (Box 29, Folder The Singing Thrush (1873). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of The Singing Thrush(first published in 1873 and later published under the title Wandering at Morn) written in pencil, with corrections and changes (some in ink) on a folded sheet of stationery. The draft is signed and dated Washington, February 28, 1873.
  - The Sleepers, about 1881; loc.00295; xxx.00264; poetry handwritten 12 leaves 11.5 x 20.5 cm (Box 29, Folder The Sleepers (1855). A.MS. corrected pages.)
    A bound copy of corrected pages of The Sleepers from the 1876 edition of Leaves of Grass. The corrections are written in ink, purple ink (faded red?) and blue pencil on every page and are for the 1881 edition of Leaves of Grass. There is a portrait of Whitman opposite a title page reading "Sleepers, by Walt Whitman, The Poet's Corrected Proof."
  - The Sobbing of the Bells, 1881; loc.00020; xxx.00302; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder The Sobbing of the Bells (1881). A.MS. drafts.)